Life is a terrible thing to sleep through.
What's Eating Gilbert Grape is a romance, drama
film directed by Lasse Hallström.
Gilbert Grape is a small-town young man with a lot of responsibility.
Chief among his concerns are his mother, who is so overweight that she can't leave the house, and
his mentally impaired younger brother, Arnie, who has a knack for finding trouble.
Settled into a job at a grocery store and an ongoing affair with local woman Betty
Carver, Gilbert finally has his life shaken up by the free-spirited Becky.
Gilbert Grape, played by Johnny Depp.
Becky, played by Juliette Lewis.
Arnie Grape, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Betty Carver, played by Mary Steenburgen.
Bonnie Grape, played by Darlene Cates.
Amy Grape, played by Laura Harrington.
What's Eating Gilbert Grape is a 1993 American coming-of-age drama film directed by Lasse Hallström, and
starring Johnny Depp, Juliette Lewis, Mary Steenburgen, Leonardo DiCaprio, and John C.
It follows a grocery store clerk, living with his dysfunctional family including his obese mother, his
mentally disabled younger brother and two sisters, in the fictional rural town of Endora, Iowa.
Peter Hedges wrote the screenplay, based on his 1991 novel of the same name.
Filming took place from November 1992 to January 1993 in various parts of Texas.
The film was well received, with Depp and DiCaprio's
performances garnering critical acclaim.
At age 19, DiCaprio received his first nominations for the Academy Award
and Golden Globe Award for Best Actor in a Supporting Role.
The film explores themes of mentally disabled, sibling
relationship, based on novel or book, widow, iowa.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.